Guide to the Fine Art Prints of New York City 1870-2003 (Bulk 1900-1940) PR 229
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Large Format Prints
  - BEAMLEY, William Jean
    - Chambers Street, New York City, 1913
      Photomechanical reproduction, color
  - BEHNKEN, William (b.1943)
    - Bronx Crossing, 1991
  - BRIEM, Gottlob L. (1899-1972)
    - The Chrysler Building, New York City, N.Y., undated
  - COHEN, Arthur Allen (b. 1928)
    - Brooklyn Bridge 1 (artist's proof), [1982]
    - Brooklyn Bridge 2 (artist's proof), [1982]
    - Brooklyn Bridge 9 (artist's proof), 1982
    - Brooklyn Bridge 9 (artist's proof), [1982]
  - CONNELL, Edwin V.D. (b. 1859)
    - [From the Tower of the Produce Exchange], with remarques of Produce Exchange Tower and Statue of Liberty], 1889
  - FERGUSON, Max (b. 1959)
    - [Waiting at the Spring Street Station (55/75), 1985
  - FIENE, ERNEST (1894-1965
    - Waterfront, Manhattan (3/100), 1931
    - Waterfront, Manhattan (89/100), 1931 (Box 1)
      Provenance
      Gift of Pam Schaffler
    - New York Skyline(21/40), 1932 (Box 1)
    - New York Skyline (26/40), 1932
  - GOLINKIN, Joseph Webster (1897-1977)
    - Black Window, ca. 1928
    - [National Horse Show at Madison Square Garden], ca. 1938
    - [Park Avenue; view south toward New York Central Building] (13/50), [1935]
    - [Speakeasy interior] (7/24), [1928]
  - HAGOPIAN, Vahan (b.1889)
    - [51st St. and Park Ave., showing St. Bartholmew's Church], undated
    - Martin Beck Theatre, undated
      lithograph, 2 copies
    - [Street Corner in Midtown]
  - HAUBEN, Daniel (b. 1956)
    - Evening Rain (46/50), 1998
    - Fire Escapes (17/35), 1983
      serigraph
  - HIOS, Theo (1908-1999)
    - Brooklyn Bridge Workers, 1937
    - War Victim, 1938
  - HUNG, Su-Li (b.1947)
    - Broken City (6/50), 2001
    - World Trade Center (2/50), 2001
  - HUNTER, F[rederick] Leo (1862-1943)
    - Coenties Slip, South Street, 1881
    - N.Y. Produce Exchange, 1887
  - KATZ, Steven
    - 57th Street Bridge, 2013 (Box FF)
      Etching
    - Ansonia 1, 2013 (Box FF)
    - Comfort Inn, 2014 (Box FF)
  - MACKAY, Donald A.
    - Farewell to the Hotel Astor (35/100), undated
  - MIELATZ, Charles Frederick William (1864-1919)
    - The Dewey Arch, 1900
  - PANTELL, Richard (b. 1927)
    - The Five Points, 1985
  - PENNEY, James (1910-1982)
    - Subway (3/10), 1932
  - SAKUYAMA, Shunji
    - [100 Garfield Place, Brooklyn], 1982
      color lithograph, monoprint
    - [465 Fourteenth Street, Brooklyn] (18/26), 1981
      color lithograph
    - [558 Second Street, Brooklyn] (12/18), 1983
    - [Room interior] (14/23), 1982
  - SANCHEZ, Emilio (1921-1999)
    - Crosstown Sunset, color lithograph (47/75), 1976 (Box Flat files)
    - Crosstown Traffic, color lithograph (4/100), 1998 (Box Flat files)
    - Hudson River View, color lithograph (8/50), 1980's (Box Flat files)
    - Loft Windows, color lithograph (42/100), 1988 (Box Flat files)
    - Looking West from My Studio, color lithograph (16/100), 1988 (Box Flat files)
    - New York on a Sunny Day, color lithograph (Box Flat files)
    - Nueva York, color lithograph (32/75), ca 1977 (Box Flat files)
    - The Shadow of the Brooklyn Bridge, color lithograph, (32/100), 1988 (Box Flat files)
    - The View from New York, color lithograph, (1/75), 1976 (Box Flat files)
  - SIMON, Tavik Frantisek (1877-1942)
    - [Broad Street with New York Stock Exchange], 1927
      color aquatint
    - [Broadway at night], [1927]
    - [New York Public Library in winter], 1927
    - [View of Lower Manhattan from Brooklyn Bridge walkway at dusk], [1927]
  - SLOAT, Richard Joel (b. 1945)
    - Not So Flat Iron(2/50), 1996
      woodblock print
    - Rising Sun (35/90), 1977
    - Walk Down St. Marks (5/90), 1994
  - TRUEBLOOD, Emily (b. 1942)
    - City Towers (2/50), 1994
    - Night Tower (31/50), 2000
  - WALLACE, William H.
    - Harlem River in 1870
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (proof), 1882
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (final), 1882
    - [New York from Staten Island (?)], 1890
    - [Post Office at Cedar and Nassau Streets], 1888
    - [Prospect Park - Apple Trees], undated
  - WERGER, Art (b.1955)
    - Daybreak (56/75), 1997
  - WHITMAN, Karen (b.1953)
    - Downtown (15/85), 2003
  - WILBUR, Lawrence Nelson (1897-1988)
    - Manhattan Mountains, 1938
    - The Spire [Empire State Building] (4/100), undated
    - Under the Bridge (6/27), 1988
    - [Produce stands] (7/75), 1976
    - [Produce stands] (9/75), 1976
- Series III: Oversize Prints
  Series III contains prints larger than 30 x 40 inches. Prints are arranged alphabetically by artist's surname and title of print; titles listed are assigned by artist while [descriptions appear in brackets]. All prints are black and white etchings unless otherwise described; dates are given if inscribed by artist or in plate.
  - BEHNKEN, William (b. 1943)
    - Lightscapes (3/50), 2003
  - GROOMS, Red (b. 1937)
    - On Your Mark, Set, Go! (9/72), 2002
    - Ruckus Taxi, 1982
    - Subway (40/75), 1971
  - HAAS, Richard (b. 1936)
    - Flatiron Building (11/60), 1973
    - Little Singer Building (36/40), 1971
  - HARRIS, Arthur John (b. 1959)
    - Flatiron (1/150), 1993
  - JACQUETTE, Yvonne (b. 1934)
    - New York Harbor Composite, 2003
  - McPHERSON, Craig (b. 1948)
    - FDR Drive, 1993
  - SELTZER, Phyllis (b. 1928)
    - Intersection, 2001
      heat transfer print
  - WERGER, Art (b.1955)
    - Attraction, 2003
  - YEWELL, J. Floyd
    - George Washington Bridge (19/150), 1931
    - George Washington Bridge, 1931
    - Goethals Bridge (59/150), undated